<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mom’s Best Friend</title>
    <subtitle>Tania Series</subtitle>
    <author><name>Kanika G</name></author>
    <link href="https://kanikag.com" />
    <link href="https://kanikag.com/category/kids-books-tania-series.atom" rel="self" />
    <id>https://kanikag.com/category/kids-books-tania-series.atom</id>
    <updated>2025-11-17T05:34:56Z</updated>
        <entry>
            <title>Tania's Midnight Adventure</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-midnight-adventure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2022-07-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Tania and her family are stranded on a mountaintop and have to spend the night there. The strange goings-on in a mysterious stone hut frighten Tania. Read on to find out all about it.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-midnight-adventure.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Tells A Story</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-tells-a-story.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2022-02-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Tania has written a fantasy story based on a scientific article. She narrates it to Sonia.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-tells-a-story.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania And The Mystery Smoker</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-and-the-mystery-smoker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2021-01-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Sonia is burned by a cigarette butt that falls in to the balcony of her home. Tania is determined to find the person who hurt her little sister and put a stop to their barbaric behavior by publicly humiliating them. But how will she catch the culprit? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-and-the-mystery-smoker.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Is Confused</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-is-confused.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2020-08-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>With so many different religions, philosophies, theories and gods, Tania is utterly confused. A discussion with Mama paves the way for a lifetime of exploration.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-is-confused.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Gets A Shock</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-a-shock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-12-02T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>One day in school, nine-year-old Tania suddenly notices blood stains in her underwear. She realizes she is bleeding, and it won’t stop. Where is the blood coming from? Is she sick? What’s going to happen? Read on to find out!
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-a-shock.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Gets Lost</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-lost.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-06-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Tania is growing up, and so is her thirst for adventure. After reading many books about kids solving mysteries and stumbling upon secret passages, Tania is craving an adventure of her own. But what happens when a fun adventure turns dangerous? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-lost.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania In A Winter Wonderland</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-in-a-winter-wonderland.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 31 of The Tania Series. Tania and her family visit Shimla again, but this time in winter. From solving a crisis to doing science experiments and enjoying winter sports and other activities, this book has it all. Read on to find out all about Tania's adventures in a winter wonderland.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-in-a-winter-wonderland.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania's Monsoon Adventure</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-monsoon-adventure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-08-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 30 of The Tania Series. Tania and her friends are on the way back from a school trip. It is pouring cats and dogs and the roads have started flooding. As the school bus crawls through a water logged street,
the engine sputters and chokes and comes to a grinding halt. The kids are stranded. What will they do?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-monsoon-adventure.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>The Boy In The Cupboard</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-the-boy-in-the-cupboard.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-06-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is a short story set in the Tania universe. Tania and her family are on vacation. Tania opens a locked cupboard to find a litle boy locked inside. What could this be all about? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-the-boy-in-the-cupboard.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Novice In The Kitchen</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-novice-in-the-kitchen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-05-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>What makes mixers explode? How does milk curdle? How does Sonia's accident improve a recipe for strawberry yoghurt? Can you make chocolate flavored bread pudding in the microwave? And how does Tania end up with glue in her tummy?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-novice-in-the-kitchen.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Gets Stitches</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-stitches.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 29 of The Tania Series. Tania's sister, Sonia, is now 2 years old. Tania loves playing with Sonia.
One day, while they are playing catch, Tania has a bad fall and her chin splits. There is blood everywhere and she needs stitches. Can Tania be brave, for Sonia's sake? What does the doctor do, to take her mind off the pain? I hear she learns something about X-rays. Wow! That sounds really exciting. Aren't you curious?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-stitches.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania's Martian Encounter</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-martian-encounter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-10-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 28 of The Tania Series. Scientists have found evidence of water on Mars. This makes big news,
so Tania is interested in the Solar system and learns a lot about it. Tania's uncle is a scientist working on the Mars project. But has he ever come across Martian life? Would he tell Tania if he had? Is it possible that Tania actually encounters Martian life? How would that happen? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-martian-encounter.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania's Slumber Party</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-slumber-party.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-09-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 27 of The Tania Series. Mama arranges a slumber party to celebrate Tania's 6th birthday. The activities mama has planned are great fun, the food is delicious and the kids get to stay up an hour past their usual bedtime chatting and playing games. But the real drama does not start till everyone is fast asleep. The silence of the night is shattered by a blood curdling scream. Who is screaming and why? What could be so frightening? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-slumber-party.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>The Blackout</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-the-blackout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-08-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 26 of The Tania Series. A worker at a construction project near Tania's housing society accidentally damaged some power cables. So the housing society and the neighbouring areas experience a blackout. After sunset it is too dark to do anything fun. Or is it? Mama shows Tania an old book and then Tania has a brilliant idea. Read on to find out what Tania and her friends do for entertainment during this pitch dark night.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-the-blackout.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Makes Trouble</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-makes-trouble.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-07-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 25 of The Tania Series. Mama has been wanting to work for a while. Finally an opportunity presents itself, so she can work from home. This is ideal for Mama. She can be home when Tania is back
from school and get some work done while Sonia sleeps. But Tania is upset that Mama has
less time for her. She decides to make it impossible for Mama to work, so she has to quit her job.
Will Tania succeed? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-makes-trouble.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Casts A Spell</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-casts-a-spell.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-06-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 24 of The Tania Series. Tania and Tanisha come across an old spell that brings bad luck.
They decide to use it on a boy who often teases them. They think it is harmless fun,
because we all know spells don't actually work. But then terrible things happen to the poor boy.
Tania feels really guilty. How did the spell work? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-casts-a-spell.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Loses A Tooth</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-loses-a-tooth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-05-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 23 of The Tania Series. One morning Tania wakes up and finds that her tooth is shaking. She is terrified, but Mama calms her down and tells her it is quite normal. Mama teaches her about the different types of teeth and explains that the baby teeth get replaced by permanent teeth. Reassured, Tania enjoys waggling her tooth and showing it off to her friends and grandparents. All is well, until Grandpa suggests a horrifying way to remove the shaking tooth. Tania starts worrying again.
Read on to find out what happens to that tooth.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-loses-a-tooth.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Visits An Art Exhibition</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-visits-an-art-exhibition.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-04-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 22 of The Tania Series. Art is Tania's favourite subject at school. When Tania sees posters advertising a local art exhibition she is keen on going for it. The exhibits are not only beautiful,
but also expose her to artistic techniques, she could never have imagined. Read on to find out
what they are.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-visits-an-art-exhibition.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania's Safari Adventure</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-safari-adventure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-03-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 21 of The Tania Series. Tania and her family go on a Jeep safari of the Gir forest national park and sanctuary. There are lions, peacocks and many more amazing animals and birds. The Jeep has a flat tire and
Tania has to get out of the Jeep while it is being fixed. She is worried about a lion coming by....
Read on to find out what happens.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-safari-adventure.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Gets Spectacles</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-spectacles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-02-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 20 of The Tania Series. Tania is having trouble reading the blackboard. Her teacher thinks she should get her eyes examined. Tania is worried about her eyesight being bad and he impending visit to the eye doctor. Mama does an experiment to explain how the eye works. This makes Tania feel better. But will her friends tease her when she gets spectacles? How will she deal with that? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-gets-spectacles.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Attends A Wedding</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-attends-a-wedding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 19 of The Tania Series. Tania and her family go to Bangalore for aunt Poonam's wedding. Join Tania as she participates in all the fun rituals and ceremonies. Tania is faced with a challenge and she comes up with a devious plan to overcome it. Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-attends-a-wedding.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Eureka!</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-eureka.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-01-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 18 of The Tania Series. Tania and her friends are playing a game. It involves fulfilling some tasks.
Tanisha, the judge, cant decide who wins. She approaches Tania's papa for help. He tells them a story about a scientist of Syracuse with a similar problem, and that helps Tanisha decide on the winner. Read on to find out how Tanisha figures it out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-eureka.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania's School Picnic</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-school-picnic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2014-12-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 17 of The Tania Series. Tania gets a pair of binoculars for her birthday. She plans a fun spying expedition with Tanisha. What starts out as fun, has a very exciting outcome. Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tanias-school-picnic.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania At School</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-at-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2014-12-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 16 of The Tania Series. Tania is a very smart and dedicated student. But she does have one irksome quality. She chatters a lot even when she should be listening to what the teacher has to say. That gets her in trouble. Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-at-school.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Tania Is A Spy</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-is-a-spy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2014-11-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is book 15 of The Tania Series. Tania gets a pair of binoculars for her birthday. She plans a fun spying expedition with Tanisha. What starts out as fun, has a very exciting outcome. Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/kids-books-tania-series-tania-is-a-spy.html</id>
        </entry>
</feed>
