<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mom’s Best Friend</title>
    <subtitle>Laughs</subtitle>
    <author><name>Kanika G</name></author>
    <link href="https://kanikag.com" />
    <link href="https://kanikag.com/category/parenting-laughs.atom" rel="self" />
    <id>https://kanikag.com/category/parenting-laughs.atom</id>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:25:05Z</updated>
        <entry>
            <title>The Bamboozling Shenanigans Of Bum Biter</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-the-bamboozling-shenanigans-of-bum-biter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-07-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My two bundles of chaos were chasing each other around the massive sofa chair in our living room. Suddenly the smaller blur spotted Papa, changed course and charged after him. The bigger blur, was unfazed by the sudden change of direction and remained in pursuit of the smaller blur.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-the-bamboozling-shenanigans-of-bum-biter.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Peas In A Pod</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-peas-in-a-pod.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-04-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>The other day, when my two daughters were on the swings in the society play area, a lady came up to me and asked if they are twins. “No!” I exclaimed surprised. Why would anyone think that? “They are sisters.” I explained. “This one is 2 and a half and the other is 5.”
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-peas-in-a-pod.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Quantumgarten: The World Of Observer Dependent Realities</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-quantumgarten.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-03-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Two adults may be given the same information, but how they receive or interpret it will be coloured by their, interests, past experiences and knowledge. Now think about how different kids interpret the same collective experiences they share in a Kindergarten class. This is a fun read.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-quantumgarten.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Of Peenytails, Ghosts, And More ...</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-of-peenytails-ghosts-and-more.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-11-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Babies can be very frustrating, but they can be very funny too. And since they are not trying to be funny, their shenanigans are so heart warming, they'll make you forget all your distractions and genuinely laugh for a few minutes. I thought I'd share some anecdotes that made me laugh.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-of-peenytails-ghosts-and-more.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Laughing Through The Terrible Twos</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-laughing-through-the-terible-twos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-09-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is a light hearted post about how the terrible two's can also be terribly cute, and remembering that may help us get through it with at least some of our sanity.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-laughing-through-the-terible-twos.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Mama Beer!</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-mama-beer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-04-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>No, this is not an April fools joke. But really, what on earth could she be talking about?</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-mama-beer.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Mischief v/s Mama: Mama's Graceful Surrender</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-mischief-vs-mama.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My toddler was quite well behaved. As far as toddlers go that is.Of course she was messy and strong willed and the terrible twos were indeed quite terrible and spilled generously over in to terrible threes. But she wasn't naughty per say. She did not make trouble to amuse herself and then laugh impishly at my frustration. She was often defiant with a purpose and sometimes sulky or clumsy but not mischievous.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-laughs-mischief-vs-mama.html</id>
        </entry>
</feed>
