<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mom’s Best Friend</title>
    <subtitle>Resources</subtitle>
    <author><name>Kanika G</name></author>
    <link href="https://kanikag.com" />
    <link href="https://kanikag.com/category/parenting-resources.atom" rel="self" />
    <id>https://kanikag.com/category/parenting-resources.atom</id>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:22:33Z</updated>
        <entry>
            <title>Easing Into Periods</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-easing-into-periods.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2023-11-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Menarche is a landmark event in a girl's life. Here is some information girls and their parents,  might find useful in the year that follows menarche.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-easing-into-periods.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Post COVID Rejuvination</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-post-covid-rejuvination.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2022-05-31T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Nothing like the great Himalayan outdoors and a stiff dose of family time amid breathtaking views to wipeout two years of lockdown cynicism.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-post-covid-rejuvination.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Pharaoh And Cleopatra</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-pharoh-and-cleopatra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2020-04-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A review of Pharaoh and Cleopatra, a computer game set in ancient Egypt, requiring clever planning and parallel information processing. Bonus: It's great for family time.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-pharoh-and-cleopatra.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>The Undervalued Artist</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-undervalued-artist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2020-03-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Art comes in many forms. If you love it, show your appreciation, or it will disappear!
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-undervalued-artist.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>A Review Of La Folie Lab</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-la-folie.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-11-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A review of La Folie Lab, a tiny French cafe tucked away on Hill road in Bandra West, Mumbai. A secret gem waiting to be discovered. What can I say? I’ve fallen for La Folie ;)
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-la-folie.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>A Summer Experiment</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-summer-experiment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-05-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>An old fashioned two week long vacation on a secluded hill top cottage in Gethia, Nainital. Read on to find out what we saw and what we learned.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-summer-experiment.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>A Review Of Wonder Park (Movie)</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-rview-of-wonder-park.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-05-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A review of Wonder Park, an animated children's movie that reminds you that everything in life is tangled up! Whether it is art and technology or happiness and sadness, they all overlap and are mixed up and that’s what makes life beautiful.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-rview-of-wonder-park.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Beat The Heat With Books</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-summer-reading-list.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-04-29T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A diverse list of books so every kid (ages 4 to 10) can find something to transport them to fascinating new worlds where they meet quirky characters and get tangled up in ticklish or exciting situations.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-summer-reading-list.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Growing Brains Cause Growing Pains</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-growing-brains-cause-growing-pains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-10-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Teenage years are trying times for kids as well as their parents. Nothing seems to make sense and for a long time the strangeness of this phase of life has been attributed to hormones going wild. But the hormones are not the only major changes taking place. Modern imaging techniques have revealed that the brain undergoes a huge transformation during adolescent years, and understanding these changes may help us understand teens better.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-growing-brains-cause-growing-pains.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Learning Disabilities And Behavioral Disorders In Children</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-learning-and-behavorial-disorders.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-10-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>What is dyslexia? How can it be detected? What can be done, to help children with dyslexia make satisfactory academic progress? What help and support is available for children with dyslexia in India? What is ADHD? What are the treatment options? What are the risk factors for oppositional defiant disorder, and how can it be treated? These are some of the issues I am going to delve in to, in this post.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-learning-and-behavorial-disorders.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Peg Board Toy Review</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-peg-board-toy-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-10-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A review of a peg board toy I got my 3 year old on her recent birthday.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-peg-board-toy-review.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>A Dentist's Views On Children's Dental Care</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-dentists-views-on-childrens-dental-care.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-09-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>An interview with Dr. Pooja Jagtiaani, about children's dental care and oral hygiene. Pooja has been practicing General and Family Dentistry in Mumbai, for the last 15 years, and regularly deals with kids. Here, she shares, useful information and helpful tips for parents.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-a-dentists-views-on-childrens-dental-care.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Have You Met Caillou</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-have-you-met-caillou.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-07-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My older one is now 5. She doesn't show much interest in TV, but occasionally wants to watch something. Personally I have nothing against TV in moderation. But I did want to find a show that would be fun for my daughter to watch and yet subtly advocate open mindedness, curiosity and sensitivity.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-have-you-met-caillou.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Monthly News Publication For Kids</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-monthly-news-publication-for-kids.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-06-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Some time ago, I received my first copy of My Paper, a monthly news publication for kids. My 5 year old daughter was so excited she wanted to read all the articles at once. Frankly in today's internet age I did not see any point in getting them a subscription to a newspaper. After all information is at their fingertips. They can look up anything they are curious about, and for fiction or activities I buy them books. So what purpose does a monthly news publication serve?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-monthly-news-publication-for-kids.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Exploitation Of Parental Love</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-exploitation-of-parental-love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-04-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>I recently read this interesting article about how advertising is effective. To summarize it targets our deepest insecurities, and then tells us that having such and such product can solve our problem. By pinching where it hurts most, it makes us worry or feel bad about our selves, and then capitalizes on our desperation or misery.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-exploitation-of-parental-love.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Busy Babies And Happy Moms</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-busy-babies-and-happy-moms.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-11-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Keeping energetic toddlers stimulated and entertained through the vacations is no mean task. I consider myself an enthusiastic mom. But finger painting, puzzles, puppet shows, story time and cooking with mommy, simply, don't fill up the day. Besides even awesome moms need some me time. So what do we do? This Diwali vacation I rediscovered Busy Beavers and they came to my rescue.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-busy-babies-and-happy-moms.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Which Baby Products Do I Buy?</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-which-baby-products-do-i-buy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-03-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Baby products! There are a lot of them out there. As a new mother it is difficult to decide which ones to buy. What will be useful and for how long? What are the pros and cons of the different varieties?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-which-baby-products-do-i-buy.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Science For All Ages</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-science-for-all-ages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-02-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>The Nehru Science Centre is a great place to take your kids to, for a half or full day family outing. Even the really little ones can enjoy watching the various exhibits at work. What better way to inspire a love for science at an early age?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-science-for-all-ages.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Meaningful Birthday Gifts For Babies</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-meaningful-birthday-gifts-for-babies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Your baby turning a year old is a very special milestone. But a one year old is not materialistic. The infant wont ask for anything. I suppose this stage will not last long. In my experience a 2 year old is not materialistic  either but that may not be so general.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-meaningful-birthday-gifts-for-babies.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Strap On Baby Carriers</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-strap-on-baby-carriers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2015-02-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>I was a student for a long time, finishing up with a doctorate in Physics at age 26.  So I was used to carrying heavy backpacks full of reference books. I think the only muscles I ever developed were those involved in walking significant distances, and those involved in carrying heavy backpacks.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/parenting-resources-strap-on-baby-carriers.html</id>
        </entry>
</feed>
