<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mom’s Best Friend</title>
    <subtitle>Relationships</subtitle>
    <author><name>Kanika G</name></author>
    <link href="https://kanikag.com" />
    <link href="https://kanikag.com/category/women-relationships.atom" rel="self" />
    <id>https://kanikag.com/category/women-relationships.atom</id>
    <updated>2025-11-17T10:25:05Z</updated>
        <entry>
            <title>Health, Romance, And Fun, All In One!</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-sporty-datenight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2019-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Here are some fun sporty activities than can liven up your date nights and family fun nights.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-sporty-datenight.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Our First Holiday Without Our Kids</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-couples-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-09-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Wondering if you should plan a short trip without your kids? We hesitated, but eventually went through with it, and for us, it worked out great. Read all about it, and a review of the gorgeous Taj Lake Palace, where we went.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-couples-time.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Cooking Up Romance</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-cooking-up-romance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-06-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Ever considered cooking with your spouse on date night? Papa and I gave it a shot and it turned out to be deliciously romantic!
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-cooking-up-romance.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Building Relationships</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-building-relationships.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-05-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>In the modern world there are many ways to travel, meet people, make friends, learn new things, debate ideologies and share laughs. That is what I learned from doing the A to Z challenge.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-building-relationships.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Mixed Feelings</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-mixed-feelings.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-12-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Susheela is having a very strange morning. Her husband, her kids, and even her employer are acting queer. Susheela is getting more anxious every second. Something is definitely going on. But what? Is it good or bad? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-mixed-feelings.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>5 Interesting Ideas For Date Night</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-five-awesome-ideas-for-date-night.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-12-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Dinner and a movie is the classic way to spend date night. But there are many other possibilities to explore. Here are some interesting ideas for date night, that can help you slow down and stay connected in a fast paced world.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-five-awesome-ideas-for-date-night.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Navigating The Relationship Maze</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-navigating-the-relationship-maze.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-05-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>In modern relationships, terms like space, boundaries, communication and secrets are often used to assess a health of a relationship. We want to have open and honest communication with our partners, and yet we want space and to set boundaries. Are these demands incompatible or can they all be satisfied in harmony?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-navigating-the-relationship-maze.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Setting Boundaries In Relationships</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-setting-boundaries-in-relationships.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-04-29T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>A blogger friend of mine recently wrote an article about being an over enthusiastic newly wed. Being ambitious, she always aimed high and marriage was no different. She took it on as something to excel at. So she was eager to tackle everything from being a working woman to running the household like clockwork. Being highly competent, she managed just that. Well at least until the couple was blessed with a beautiful bundle of chaos and then the expectations she had built up back fired and caused marital issues that required a lot of work to fix.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-setting-boundaries-in-relationships.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Anniversary In A Locked Room</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-anniversary-in-a-locked-room.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2017-04-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Papa and I have been together for a little over 16 years and today is our 9th wedding anniversary, and we spent over an hour, locked together in a room. Aren't you curious about what we did? I'll tell you in a moment. But here is some back story first.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-anniversary-in-a-locked-room.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>When I Lost My Marbles</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-when-i-lost-my-marbles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-11-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My husband (referred to as Papa in my blogs, because that is what I often call him, since our daughter christened him Papa in spite of all our efforts to get her to call him daddy) and I met in degree college, whilst doing our B.Sc in physics. I had hoped to join IIT's Physics department, but I did not get through the second round of JEE (IIT's prestigious Joint Entrance Exam). Having spent 2 years working tirelessly on getting through the JEE, I had hardly considered what I would do if I did not get in.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-when-i-lost-my-marbles.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Competition In Relationships</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-competition-in-relationships.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-11-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Papa (my husband) and I like to spend a few hours a week discussing our lives, or our relationship or Physics or some esoteric subject. This weekend we were talking about something and somehow we ended up on the subject of competition. We are both fiercely competitive people. But somehow we realised that we don't really compete against each other. So we thought about it. How did that come to be, we wondered.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-competition-in-relationships.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>The Little Things</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-the-little-things.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-10-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Papa, and I have been a couple since I was 18. We met in degree college, and 2 years later we were graduate students in different universities in the US. Now we have been together for 15 years and married for 8 years and here are some heart warming memories.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-the-little-things.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Whose Wedding Is It Anyway?</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-whose-wedding-is-it-anyway.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-08-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Weddings, the tension, the drama, the compromises and how I enjoyed it all
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-whose-wedding-is-it-anyway.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>No Guarantees In Love. Only Signs</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-no-guarantees-in-love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-04-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Is love really blind? Or are there signs we read and follow at least at a subconscious level?
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-no-guarantees-in-love.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Twenty Years And Going Strong</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-twenty-years-and-going-strong.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2016-04-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>It all began one summer afternoon. I was barely 13 and suffering from an upset stomach. My grandmother introduced us. She said I'd feel better. And indeed I did. Since that day, it has been an awesome 20 years, together, for us.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-relationships-twenty-years-and-going-strong.html</id>
        </entry>
</feed>
