<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mom’s Best Friend</title>
    <subtitle>Health</subtitle>
    <author><name>Kanika G</name></author>
    <link href="https://kanikag.com" />
    <link href="https://kanikag.com/category/women-health.atom" rel="self" />
    <id>https://kanikag.com/category/women-health.atom</id>
    <updated>2025-11-13T15:22:33Z</updated>
        <entry>
            <title>Fast And Furious</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-fast-and-furious.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2024-01-31T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Intermittent fasting is all the rage these days. But can someone prone to being hangry manage it? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-fast-and-furious.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>COVID-19: Experts Brainstorm For Solutions</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-covid-brainstorm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2020-05-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>From hydroxychloroquine and BCG vaccinations, to blood thinners and pulse oximeters, scientists have left no avenue unexplored. Simultaneously, universities and labs are working intensely on developing a vaccine. So here are somethings one should know.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-covid-brainstorm.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Sexual Dysfunction</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-sexual-dysfunction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-10-29T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Sexual dysfunction may be embarassing to talk about, but living in denial can have far reaching effects on marital and family life.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-sexual-dysfunction.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Zest For Life</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-z-zest-for-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>This is my final entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues. If you have stuck with me so far, you know about all the frightening challenges the female body may have to overcome. But the point is, we are thriving and growing as a species. Clearly, we are crossing these hurdles with room to spare. So this last post, is a toast to women world over, for our resilience, endurance and most of all, for our zest for life. Cheers. Read on and feel uplifted.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-z-zest-for-life.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Yeast Infection</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-y-yeast-infection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twenty fifth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge, with the theme women's health issues, is about yeast infections. We have all had them at some point. Sometimes we may not even notice them, but read on for some interesting information on possible causes, and about recurring yeast infections, which can be quite bothersome.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-y-yeast-infection.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>X- Rays, Xenophobia And Pregnancy</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-x-ray.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twenty fourth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about how pregnancy makes us so protective, that we may worry about everything from X-rays to foreigners. It's not crazy, but we need to put these fears in perspective. Read on to learn about which X-rays can be harmful for pregnancy, and why pregnancy may trigger xenophobia.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-x-ray.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Weighty Woes</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-w-weighty-woes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twenty third entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about weight gain. Women often worry about their figures and think of extra pounds in terms of the optics. How will I look? But being overweight can cause serious health problems. Recent research also shows, that women gain weight more easily than men, so we need to be extra careful.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-w-weighty-woes.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Vagina Wars</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-v-vaginosis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twenty second entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about vaginosis. The vagina is a vibrant ecosystem of a variety of microbial life competing to thrive, and keeping each other in check. What happens when this delicate balance is disturbed? Read on to find out.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-v-vaginosis.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Urinary Tract Infection</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-u-uti.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twenty first entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about urinary tract infections, which a woman has about a 40 to 60 percent chance of contracting at some point in her life.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-u-uti.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Thyroid Disorders</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-t-thyroid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twentieth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about thyroid related problems, which are eight times more common in women than in men!
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-t-thyroid.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Sexually Transmitted Diseases</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-s-stds.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My nineteenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about sexually transmitted diseases, how they affect women in particular, and what precautions one needs to take to prevent them.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-s-stds.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Rheumatoid Arthritis</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-r-rheumatoid-arthritis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My seventeenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about rheumatoid arthritis, a serious autoimmune condition, that disproportionately affects women. 70 % of those who suffer form it are women.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-r-rheumatoid-arthritis.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Queasy</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-q-queasy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My seventeenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about queasiness during morning sickness aka a prolonged tour of hell. And you thought that labor was bad! Read on to find out more about it.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-q-queasy.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Period.</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-p-period.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My sixteenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about periods. Love it, hate it or hardly notice it, it's going to come knocking every month for few decades, well unless you're knocked up, that is. Read on to find out about ways in which periods could be more comfortable and some of the complications associated with them.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-p-period.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Orgasm</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-o-orgasm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My fifteenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about the female orgasm. The female orgasm is a hushed up taboo subject, with a complicated history and has had loads of misconceptions associated with it over the years. But there are health benefits and health conditions associated with it too. Read on to learn more about this scarcely talked about subject.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-o-orgasm.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>NICU</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-n-nicu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My fourteenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about neonatal intensive care units. While this is more about infant care, it strongly affects mothers too, and not just indirectly. The time when the baby is in the NICU, is often an emotionally stressful time following either a difficult pregnancy or complicated child birth. While the mother herself is recovering physically, the emotional stress is daunting, and she can use all the support she can get from medical facilities, family and society.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-n-nicu.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Menopause</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-m-menopause.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My thirteenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about menopause, which signifies the end of menstruation and fertility. While one might expect that to be a huge relief from bleeding every month, our reproductive system takes one last swing at making us miserable, before it shuts down for good. But there is an interesting evolutionary theory to explain why menopause occurs. Read on to learn about it.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-m-menopause.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Labor</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-l-labor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My twelveth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about the labor of love and it is not pretty. I am talking about labor and child birth. When I was pregnant, in the last month I wished I knew what labor and child birth really felt like, so I could be mentally prepared for it. But there were few people sharing their experiences in detail. So, here I will share my own experience in detail and I hope it helps some of you there in your last months, wondering what is to come. Of course, no two experiences are alike as you will see. I have included some useful informative links as well.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-l-labor.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Kidney Disease</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-k-kidney-disease.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My eleventh entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about kidney disease. Kidney disease affects a significant fraction of the total population, but women face certain unique challenges, because of their reproductive system. Read on to learn about the symptoms, causes and treatments for kidney disease.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-k-kidney-disease.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Jaundice During Pregnancy</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-j-jaundice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My tenth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about jaundice during pregnancy. Jaundice during pregnancy, though rare, can be a serious issue. Yet some of the early symptoms can often be confused with morning sickness. Read on to learn more about it.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-j-jaundice.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Ischemic Stroke</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-i-ischemic-stroke.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My ninth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about ischemic strokes. Strokes are the fourth leading cause of death in women and ischemic strokes account for about 88% of all strokes. 60% of all stroke deaths are among women and strokes kill twice as many women as breast cancer does.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-i-ischemic-stroke.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Heart Disease</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-h-heart-disease.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>Heart disease is the number one cause of death in women, affecting one in three or four women. Symptoms of a heart attack in women, are quite different from widely known symptoms, which are more common among men. Read on to  acquaint yourself with the risk factors and other details of heart diseases that are different in women than they are in men.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-h-heart-disease.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Gestational Diabetes</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-g-gestational-diabetes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My seventh entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about gestational diabetes, a growing problem that seems to have more serious implications than anticipated earlier. However there is no need to panic. In most cases it can be easily managed. Read on to find out more about it.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-g-gestational-diabetes.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Fertility</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-f-fertility.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My sixth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about fertility or the lack thereof. When a couple can't conceive, it is usually assumed that something is wrong with the woman, especially if she is over 30, but that is not always the case. In this post I will discuss the various causes of infertility and talk about the magic of in vitro fertilization.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-f-fertility.html</id>
        </entry>

        <entry>
            <title>Endometriosis</title>
            <link href="https://kanikag.com/women-health-e-endometriosis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            <updated>2018-04-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
            <summary>My fifth entry for the A to Z blogging challenge with the theme women's health issues is about endometriosis, a painful womb condition, that usually remains undiagnosed for several years.
</summary>
            <id>https://kanikag.com/women-health-e-endometriosis.html</id>
        </entry>
</feed>
